AKHIL REDDY

https://66249956e5de076c3931bed9-magical-profiterole-a6fce1.netlify.app/About +1(469) 6597139 \diamond Columbus, OH

Edara.akhilreddy@gmail.com \lefthanton https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhilreddy0609/

OBJECTIVE

Experienced software developer with over 4 years of involvement in the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), adeptly contributing to all phases. Interested in positions involving both front-end and back-end. familiar with the DevOps.Completed course work in Information Technologies and management with 33credits. Currently seeking career opportunities in both contract and full-time roles.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology, University of Memphis

2022 - 2023

Coursework:- Depth in HTML CSS, React Advanced, Programming with JavaScript artificial intelligence(AI), Version Control, AWS Cloud Technical Essentials, Migrating to the AWS Cloud, Scrum Masters

SKILLS

Technical Skills Soft Skills Methodologies Java, ReactJS, React-native, artificial intelligence, python, HTML, CSS, tailwind-CSS, Spring, MySQL,

 $Communication, Problem-solving, teamwork, Time\ management, Continuous\ Learning$

Agile, Waterfall

EXPERIENCE

Pristenit INC

Software Engineer

May 2023 - Present

Dallas, TX

- Reduced the processing time of reporting service by 65percent by implementing caching resulting in 20percent cost reduction.
- Build RestAPIs using nodeJS, MongoDB.
- Developed new futures, functionality, and capability for client web site by using BootStrap.
- Worked with DBAs in designing the database Triggers, Views and Indexes to implement optimized SQL queries.
- Developed microservices using REST framework and springboot.
- Manage and support customer environments in Microsoft Azure cloud.

Analyst [Master's project]

Jan 2022 - May 2023

Memphis, TN

University of Memphis

- Developed complex SQL queries and utilized Excel and data visualization tools to create meaningful reports and dashboards.
- Utilized Tableau to design and develop interactive dashboards and reports, providing insights on key business metrics and performance indicators.
- Solid understanding of database management and querying using SQL, Excellent problem-solving, gathering data, and critical-thinking skills.

Software Engineer

May2018 - Nov 2021

Jasam Technologies

India

- Worked in all phases of SDLC such as requirements gathering, designing, developing, testing, and deploying, and Involved in developing mobile applications by using React-Native.
- Developed application styling by using Tailwind CSS with react-native and React native Elements to elevate app designs
- Experienced by integrating push notification services for mobile Push Notification Service (APNS) into React Native applications, enabling real-time communication with users.

- Proficient in designing and developing RESTful Web APIs to enable communication between client-side and server-side applications.
- Designed and implementation of public and private facing websites on AWS Cloud.

PROJECTS

Payment Processing API Developed a RESTful API using Java, Spring Boot, and Apace CXF for processing payments, ensuring secure and efficient transactions. Utilized Web Sockets for real-time communication. Customer Dashboard: Built a customer dashboard application using Angular, Spring Boot, and Oracle database, providing real-time insights and enabling data-driven decision-making.

Supply chain optimization: For the transportation we need to analyze the data, Then Created a data model in Snowflake that reflects the transportation operations. That can include tables for shipping routes, carrier information, transit times, fuel costs, and delivery times. Define the relationships between these tables and set up any necessary constraints, such as foreign key constraints.

Integrate the transportation data into PowerBI using ETL (extract, transform, load) processes. and used Talend tool to automate this process and ensure that the data is accurate and up to date. Used Snowflake's integration with PowerBI to create dashboards and reports that communicate my findings. For analyze the transportation data and to identify opportunities to reduce costs, used Snowflake's SQL.